Good morning. It's Monday, March 9th.
Thank you for tuning in to Dprogram with
Ted Rall and John Kiriakou.
Uh John Kiriakou either looks very
different or he's being substituted by
Robbie West. I'm not sure which it is.
Robbie West is our producer.
Um John is traveling this morning and we
were originally told that John would be
joining us for about half the show and
then Robbie would probably have to fill
in for the last half while John ran from
one flight to the next. I kind of wanted
to see him running through the terminal
um and uh you know, with the all
jostling while he did the show. But we
don't know where he is. We texted him
this morning and went straight to
uh text the text went undelivered and
his voicemail goes straight to his
phone. So straight you know, straight no
ring. So obviously he's still on the the
first flight and hasn't gotten off.
Hasn't deplaned as they say in the
awkward terminology of aviation. So
thanks for joining us. If John does pop
in and grace us with his presence, we'll
just put him on. So this is like this
may be
to Dprogram with Ted Rall and John
Kiriakou. It may not be. It may be
partly John. I don't know.
Well, I mean Is that a full sum enough
explanation, Robbie? Well, it's kind of
like American foreign policy. You never
quite know what you're going to get. I
mean
Or what or what the or Or what the
reasons are.
Uh
Uh no, reasons for suckers. You don't
need reasons. Just just need to just bow
your head bovinely and say uh absolutely
my dear sweet orange Jesus, whatever it
is that you think is best. I've fully I
fully consent to whatever it is that you
want to do. And that's kind of like
how the how our show is when it comes to
John's travel schedule because well,
he is an international man of mystery.
He's always going. There's nothing going
on the world causing chaos.
And so
um everything is running along as it
should be.
Indeed. As as it all for the best in
this best of all possible worlds
as they said in Candide. Um so
Robbie, before we get to obviously that
we're going to be talking about the
economy, we're going to be talking about
Iran, we're going to be talking about
the ecological disaster that's
unfolding in Tehran that probably will
have consequences for years to come. But
I wanted to ask you and I know I don't
think we've talked about this much but I
talked a little bit about it with my DMZ
co-host Scott Stanton last week.
Um
the more I game it out, right? I when I
the way my mind works is it's kind of
like a I look like trying to solve a
Rubik's Cube, right? Like I turn it
around, look at one side, then I look at
the other side, then I'm like and it
takes me a while to kind of like game
things out from the when I don't
understand what's going on. I think we
can all say, you know, Trump is not does
not want us to understand what's going
on or why he's doing things.
Um but I the more I think about it, the
more I think he's going to cancel this
election and as well as the presidential
one. And the reason I think that is
if he doesn't cancel
the if he if he leaves the presidency,
he becomes vulnerable to
you know, all the the felony charges
that are pending against him in the
federal courts will resume in 2020 on
January 20th, 2029. And lawfare will go
back and he could very well be facing
prison again.
Um he or me or you, any of us would do
anything to avoid that, anything. And
the and I'm thinking, well, so he has to
avoid it. The only way he can avoid it
is by having is coming up with some
excuse to cancel these elections. And
you know, you'd start with the midterm
cuz people won't care that much about
the midterm. And then they're kind of
used to not that not having an election
by 2028, so maybe they won't really
freak out and by that time we'll have
more authoritarianism. I know it's a lot
of ifs, right? But the basically bottom
line is no 2020 election working
backwards. Let's start with 2026 no
election. And therefore Trump can stay
in office. And therefore everything else
makes sense if you think you think about
it that way because
if he doesn't need if he doesn't care
about popular will, well, a war is
always a good excuse for a national
emergency, right? Incoming attack,
whatever. Um and you don't really care
about getting, you know, buying from the
public because after all, you're not
really running again. And not And your
party's not really running again. Well,
well, well, you got to remember. I mean,
at the end of the day, all we're doing
is adopting a Ukrainian style of
democracy. It's it's it's very
streamlined. It's not sloppy. There's no
corruption.
You don't have to worry about no
campaign finance. You don't have to
worry about the those pesky election
laws. You don't have to worry about
>> debates.
Yeah, I mean, it's it's a very
streamlined system. You get to vote for
the party and man of your choice that is
offered, which is conveniently one.
And it just makes things really
efficient.
I I don't have a problem with this. It's
What do you think? Do you think I I
mean, you you can just say Ted, you're
you're paranoid as [__] Shut up. I
mean, what do you think?
Well, I agree with you.
And I I I mean, 6 months ago I would
have I would have thought that you had
TDS.
3 months ago I would have thought that
you had TDS.
>> And I never had TDS as you know. No, no,
I mean, you're a very fair-minded
person. You're much more fair-minded
than I am. I'm just trying to think like
what I would do if I were him.
You do whatever you want. I mean,
seriously, who's going to stop you?
Who's going to stop him?
I was talking to Santos yesterday uh and
he's like, well, would the American
people put up with that? I said, you
tell me how it looks. Do you think this
is like a real country like Pakistan
where 2 million people would have head
out into the streets and ready to have a
revolution? No. We would have 200 sad
people in Union Square Park in New York
City. You'd have 150 in Lafayette Park
across from the White House. Nothing
would happen. They would do who The
Democratic Party's not going to do
anything. The media's not going to do
anything. Who's going to stop them?
Well, the thing is even Okay,
serious question for you. You're the
lefty here on the show. I'm I'm the
far-right extremist.
Can you explain to me, seriously,
on a postcard, what are the differences
between the Republican and the
Democratic parties? What are the policy
differences? Where do they differ on any
of these
>> about style at this point. Well, I guess
you could say, I mean, you could say the
immigration policy is different, right?
Like the demo But mass deportations were
bigger under Obama than they are under
Trump. Um and they were definitely, you
know, maybe not as, uh, you know, open
in the streets of major cities. But it
was basically the same policy. I mean
>> Well, well, sure.
>> policies are about the are are the same
for both parties. They're both
capitalist parties. They don't care
about working-class people at all. Um
No, I mean, I take your point, but I
mean, I mean, I guess obviously the
Democrats would rather be feeding at the
trough, but they can fundraise
out of power just as easily as as being
in power. In some ways more easily.
Well, I mean, that's true. And here's
the
here's the thing. Here's where I would
push back on you a little bit about
Obama is that he counted people who were
turned away at the borders deportations.
So, he's kind of inflated his numbers.
So,
there's that.
Um
Also, I think it's very I think it's
fair to say, honestly, that this is
government by donor, i.e., government by
oligarch. If we If the United States
government system
was any other was any other country
we would call that country an oligarchy
and rightly so because it is.
So, why can't we just be honest about
what is it we are? We are an oligarchy.
The government does not fear the people
and if the government does not have a
healthy does not have a healthy fear of
the government, how can you possibly
have a representative government? You
can't. By definition, you can't.
And like I said, nothing is going to
happen if if these elections are
suspended. I mean, there would be, you
know, some very highly peaceful and
therefore useless protests, but that's
about it. Um okay, well, we're going to
obviously follow that, you know, line of
of of inquiry, but we do have to talk
about Iran first and foremost today. So,
um as we uh
it's now 9 minutes to past the hour of
9:00 here in New York City. The stock
market opens up in 21 minutes. Um
futures on the Dow Jones Industrial
Average are down 1,000 points. That's
after a major sell-off all last week. Um
and we're looking at oil prices. This is
shocking. Um just a few weeks ago uh oil
was trading at $60 a barrel. Right now,
we're at 102.64.
So, that is a 67
or more percent increase in uh crude oil
prices over the course of less than a
month. Um that is an oil shock that that
can only really be compared to OPEC. I
mean, you know, in in the oil crisis in
the mid-70s that I grew up with. I mean,
it's major. I mean, this is going to
have a ripple effect through the
economy. It's another reason that I
don't think um you know, President Trump
or the Republicans are going to dare
face the electorate this fall because
they're going to get destroyed. I mean,
people are going to just vote vote
against the incumbency, which is what
you do in a two-party system, where you
hate both parties. And the They're
They're really I mean, the politics of
this are super super ugly. I mean, it's
These prices are not going to go down
anytime soon. Trump says it's temporary.
I'm like, "Sure. I mean, in the long
run, everything's temporary, but we'll
all be dead, too." to quote Milton
Friedman.
Yeah, I mean, to be compared to what?
I mean, this is going to be massive. I
mean, it already is massive. I mean, you
know, you you've got the Strait of
Hormuz is effectively closed. Uh you
know, container ships, oil tankers are
stuck. Um you know, nobody with half a
brain is going to try to run that
straight except for Iranian-flagged
vessels. So, you know, I mean,
you the you you're you're just this And
the stock market is nervous as [__]
Robbie, why is the uh
Why is Donald Trump not scared of the
economic impact here? Because he doesn't
care. I mean,
listen, at the end of the day, and Ted,
you know that this but anybody, you're
you're a freaking communist of of all
people.
This is the case I was trying to make
with Achilles Lorea last week
was that rising prices
impacts workers and the poor and the
middle class more than it does the rich.
That is a statement of fact. If you're
insulated from that, if you don't go and
shop for your own groceries or go fill
up your own gas tank, or if you're
making, you know, $20,000 a month or
more,
>> prices, quick interjection, right? Gas
prices have now gone up a full over a
full dollar a gallon in a week. In a
week. Yeah. Anyway, go ahead.
Well, I mean, that's just what I'm
saying though. I mean, you know,
Trump doesn't care. It does It's not a
crisis for him if the cost of
transportation goes up, if the cost of
oil goes up, if the cost of food goes
up. That's an investment opportunity.
That's the point I was trying to make
last week is that yeah, I mean, you're
over here talking about bankers and
investors. I get it. You're a wealth
management guy. I understand. That's
your business model. For you, this is
good.
But for people who Are you trying to
root hog or die? Are you talking about
Achilles Lares? Yeah.
But if you're trying to root hog or die,
this is a crisis. And the absolute last
thing that you want to do
is have a pissed off electorate go vote.
Here's the question. And I mean this
sincerely, again, because you're a man
of the left.
What is the difference between the
Democrat and the Republican? One's going
to drop a bomb with an American flag,
the rainbow flag? What is the policy
difference?
Would the Democrats end this war? Would
they put BB Netanyahu in his place?
Would they tell the Israel lobby to go
screw themselves? Would they declare
independence
from the cabal that's running Washington
D.C.? The answer all these questions,
and we both know this, is no. So, what's
the difference?
Why would you go vote? Why would you
care? Why would you waste Why would you
waste your precious gas to go vote in a
meaningless election that will change
absolutely nothing?
Well, I mean, well, that's right. I
mean, who's going to [__] die over an
election? Um Adam Tube over on YouTube
says, uh "Ted, why can't the people
dissolve Congress and House and reset
with tougher vetting?" Um well, first of
all, only a certain percentage of House
seats Well, no, that's not even true.
That's the Senate. But the people can't
just dissolve the House every, uh you
know, whenever they want. We don't have
a parliamentary system. So, it doesn't
work that way. Uh we have to wait for
the election. It's every 2 years. Um and
a lot of congressmen effectively run
unopposed. In some cases, actually run
unopposed. Um
you know, it always shocks me, but two
out of three elected offices in this
country, like in a lot of state house,
state Senate seats,
have literally one-party rule, where the
candidate runs, there's one party, and
there's no opposing party on the other
And that happens even in big cities like
here in New York, there's tons of
positions like judgeships where the
Democrats run unopposed.
I mean the the closest thing honestly
that the American system had well it we
used to have to nullifying federal law
was called nullification conveniently
enough and there are times in US history
that has been used. That's the whole
argument between states rights versus
federal supremacy.
Uh that argument was settled on April
19th, 1865. I believe it was settled
wrongly.
But no
there we are. I mean
the mechanism for a for the states to
check the federal government is baked
into the Constitution in the 9th and
10th amendments. You can the states
themselves can refuse to follow federal
law.
They can do this. That is a power that
they have.
The problem is is that all of our
governors and all of our legislatures
are so cucked and so brainwashed that
they simply will not do it. No, they
won't. They just won't do it. Um is it
rational is saying that the Dow's at
50,000? Just I beg to differ that the
Dow is actually at 47,500
and it is going to drop another thousand
points at as soon as the opening bell
goes off. Um let's thank you very much
Brady Okerlund for the $19.99 donation
on YouTube. Hey Ted, quick question. If
regime change and escalation don't work
what actually stops Iran and its proxies
from getting bolder? It feels like years
of restraint and limited consequences
haven't really changed their behavior.
You know, I think it's you know, I think
that's maybe one way to look at it from
the western point of view. Another way
to look at it is from their point of
view, right? Where the Iranians feel
that they've had measured responses to
US and Israeli provocations like the
assassination of General Soleimani 6
years ago.
Um new the the attacks against the
nuclear program in the and I do mean not
nuclear weapons, I mean nuclear energy
program in Iran. And they you know, sort
of had like some performative drone
attacks where they sort of notified in
advance. Here here come drones. Here
here they come.
Uh but I think for the Iranians they
know they're as John said last week
several times
they're in an existential battle for
their lives and I guess
to me this is you know, well, what stops
Iran from and its proxies from getting
bolder? Well, you know what they say
like the song says from the 70s freedom
is another word for nothing left to
lose, right? I mean they they don't
they've had they've had to deal with US
sanctions for 47 years. Um they had as
soon as their revolution happened, they
had to deal with
our Iraqi proxies attacking them. Um you
know, they they've they've put up with a
lot of [__] from us over the years. And
yes, they've struck back, but I mean you
know, it's warmongering 101, right? What
you do is you one side you attack the
other side over and over and if they
respond, then you just claim that the
war began on that date.
And and you pretend that you're just
responding to them. That's
all that you're dealing with here. And
parenthetically, I just want to say that
I hate daylight savings time. Um yes.
Uh anyway. So, let's see. Okay, we have
a few more questions and then we'll talk
about the ecosidal maniacs who are
destroying Tehran. So, is it rational
says breaking news US urges all
Americans out of southern Turkey
non-essential consulate staff in Adana.
I mean that's we've seen that kind of
thing all over the Middle East where
consular and ambassadorial
representation is being shut down.
So, I mean you know, that that region is
spinning out of control. Pittsburgh
dude, the illusion of our elections is
that by having them, it cancels any
change. No matter who we vote for, we
get John McCain. I like that. Yeah, I
wish I could say he's wrong. He's not.
And also, is it rational? Uh one thing I
always point out about the the Dow
50,000, that was straight up a jab at
Pam Pam Bondi. But, no, when she was
testifying before Congress, I guess you
call it testifying. I don't know what
you'd say in in the real world. When she
just kept saying, "Oh, the Dow's over
50,000."
>> Performing. Yeah, I mean, uh now now the
the only thing she had going for her now
no longer exists because of a war her
boss started. And her boss is not Trump,
it's Bibi Netanyahu. Trump's middle
management, let's just be honest.
Uh join By the way, just if you're just
joining us,
uh John Kiriakou is trying to join the
show between flights,
uh and we just haven't heard
heard hide nor hair of him. So, uh we'll
we'll see if he shows up. If he does,
we'll pop him on right away, of course,
obviously. Um
So, uh let's see, both part Yeah. Uh oh,
thanks for the dollar from Unsung Pat.
The difference is where they deposit
their donations. Don't blame the
politicians, they're doing exactly what
a politician does as defined, one who is
actively involved or skilled in
politics.
Hm, fair, but they're also corrupt.
Unsung Pat also said, "A republic if we
if we can keep it, your boyfriend
uh your BF, Robbie, can you remind me
where the power lies in a republic and
which branch of government derives that
power?" Mike S is dollar sign dollar
sign dollar sign c r e a m.
Uh well, it depends on what power it is
that you're talking about, at least
what's supposed to be. Uh you know
when the United States was was first
founded, there were actually four
branches of government. You had the
executive, you had the legislative, you
had you had the judicial, and then you
had the states themselves. That Those
are the four pillars.
Now we have three.
Of those three, these the second one,
the legislative has completely seated
its authority to the executive. So I
don't really know what powers any other
branch of government has. I mean, sure
you have the Supreme Court that can come
out and say, "Oh, in our opinion this is
right or this is wrong."
But it's up to the executive to enforce
those decisions.
So I I don't know.
I mean the the system doesn't work
anymore.
I mean
Or is it working exactly the way that it
was intended to?
No, I mean that's obviously not true
because
the the founding fathers were incredibly
suspicious of exactly what is that we
have now. They wanted a diluted power
system
where you had separation of powers.
And but the majority of the powers
reserved to the states and to the
people.
I mean Yeah, they Well, they didn't they
I mean, correct me if if I'm wrong,
Robbie, but I mean my understanding was
that they expected that all the branches
of government would be jealously
guarding the prerogatives and would
fight for to protect them, right? Yep.
And and that I guess what they never
counted on was systemic corruption where
people would be willing to be bought off
and would be sold at a relatively low
price and be you know, like look at
imagine being a member of Congress under
under Speaker Mike Johnson where you're
just a rubber stamp. I mean I mean it
must be very boring. You don't really
you know, they're not really part of the
conversation or you know, the or you
know, be in in the court system where
you know, you issue an order and it just
gets ignored and brushed off. I mean
what you know, I mean it's got to be so
dispiriting. Like what's the point?
Well, that's the question I have. What's
the point of having a Congress? What
Serious question, what do they do?
Can somebody explain to me what does
Congress do? Like they can't even kill
daylight savings time.
I know. Well, you know what's so funny
is the pending the pending there is a
law that's been pending to get rid of
the time change, but Robbie, this is so
funny, right? So, the
average American would get 17 minutes of
sleep per night additional according to
studies
if we had standard time year-round. Now,
that might
17 minutes might not sound like a lot,
but imagine if you, you know, if you
have an extra hour every 4 days, right?
So, roughly 90, you know, full hours of
sleep a year, that's going to impact our
national health, right? In a in a
favorable way.
So, what's
every expert says we just need to get
rid of of daylight savings time and just
have standard time. So, the law that's
pending before Congress does the exact
opposite and keeps us on daylight
savings time forever and gets rid of
standard time.
And and it's because we're children,
because we like have it we like getting
out of work at 5:00 at night and having
a little bit of light to drive home
with.
But, meanwhile, our kids would be having
to go to go to school in the pitch dark
in the morning.
Well, there's that, but also, do you
remember what my previous job was before
I start working for you full-time,
right?
I do.
So, one thing I can tell you with
absolute certainty, the number of heart
attacks and stroke go up by about 7%
for the first 3 months after time
change.
That is a statistical fact.
People, I mean, I know right now I feel
like a little bit like like like I was
thrown like I was out partying last
night. You know, I mean, I feel like
[__] this morning.
I'm a little jet-lagged, and it's only
an hour. It's not like I I just flew to
Baku.
Yeah, it sucks. Um, Sneaker Dad, thank
you so much for the generous donation of
$100. Do you think the Don might get his
regime change, only not the one he
wanted, i.e. Cutter, UAE? You know, that
is a a good question and one that I also
want to ask John
when he shows up. I'm sure we'll have
John back tomorrow at least. Um
but yeah, I think there's a chance of
that, right? I mean, look, the Iranian
government could fall. It could, but I
just think that's not likely. I mean, by
the way, they've appointed obviously
Ali Khamenei's son,
Mojtaba, is now the new supreme leader.
Israel's of course threatening to kill
him.
You know, he's Shia, he doesn't care.
Um they're like, but
he's probably also like, you killed my
dad. You know,
I know what's in the mail here.
But I could see the I could see a lot of
the I could see the Emiratis and you
know, their street is restive and does
not agree with their governments, you
know, tacit support for Israel against a
fellow Muslim country, even if they're
Shia.
Well, it's just crazy because that
You know, for those of you who do not
follow Ted on on X, I highly recommend
that y'all do it because one of the
things I've started doing is I've
started animating his cartoons because I
don't have enough to do.
So I am now animating his cartoons.
And one of the cartoons that I animated
is is uh
this guy watching the TV pointing at it
said, "Look at those Chinese and those
Iranians protesting for their rights."
And then his wife speaks up and said,
"Honey, that's Minneapolis."
And it just it breaks the guy's brain.
And here we are, Trump is calling for
mass protests.
While by the way engaging collective
punishment, waging war against the
people in Tehran, not the government of
Tehran, the people of Tehran, which is a
war crime.
Calling for them to protest.
Meanwhile
if you try to protest here in the United
States
at best you just don't get a permit,
which why you need a permit to protest
breaks my brain and and in the republic
>> It's I mean, like if we have a First
Amendment, why do you need a Why do you
need a parade permit to protest? You you
don't.
I mean, it's it's dumb. It's just like
Kevin you got to get a license to to get
a gun. You don't need to do that. I
mean, Right. No, you I I mean, I agree.
If you have a Second Amendment, then why
do you need that? Yeah. So, I mean, the
the fact that the Trump administration
cracks down on protests here in this
country whenever Americans can rouse
themselves get and get enough vigor to
actually go out on a sunny day and chant
for an hour on the side of a road and it
that that's considered um uh uncouth.
Meanwhile, he wants to go and encourage
the people of Iran to protest at the
same time while he tries to squelch it
here.
Uh peak hypocrisy.
Uh not a Wu Evan M. Not a Wu-Tang guy,
Ted. You know, I'm a punk and new wave
guy.
That's just this is This is what I was
just listening to before the show. Uh
anyway. Um All right. So, and and the
fact that it's a CD tells you how old I
am. Although, I heard from the my my
local CD store owner that CDs are coming
back.
Uh all things old are coming back. Uh my
son, he has a record player.
And he's been
>> Yeah, he's been buying Mighty Robins.
Vinyl is Vinyl's been back for decades,
though. I mean,
I mean, vinyl represents a significant
percentage of music sales in the United
States and it just keeps going up. Uh
it's real It's really weird. Um okay, so
let's see. Um
I'm trying to go work through the
questions here. Uh Skinny Inchy, what do
you think Do we think uh Benjamin
Netanyahu knows Trump is in the Epstein
files? Maybe because they sold the info
or he was there and that's why Trump is
so easily bombing Iran. I mean,
certainly there's been a lot of uh
discussion about this war being a
distraction from the Epstein files.
I think it's a contributing factor. I
don't think it's the main thing. What do
you think?
No, I mean
it's
Ted, I mean you're mentioned in in the
Epstein files. Everybody Everybody is
mentioned in in the Epstein files.
>> Clovis. No, I mean
this is about money and influence
peddling.
The United States government is the
cheapest horse government that any uh
any lobby can buy and the Zionist lobby
has got more money than just about
anybody else and so they use that money
to buy Congress like a bunch of cheap
[__] and that's how they get what they
want. Don't forget uh 20 years ago, I
want to say it was 20 years ago. It
could have just been 15. Bibi was caught
on mic talking about how he owns
Congress.
That he owns Congress. Hmm. Is he wrong?
No, he's not wrong. Look where we are.
Does Congress care about what the
American people want or does Congress
care about what Israel wants? I mean but
we've I mean basically you and I I mean
we've been buying the the line that uh
you know, we're doing this war for
Israel but it's actually worse than that
cuz we're literally holding hands with
them. They're not even like behind the
scenes. It's literally the entire world
sees the US and Israel together
launching a war of choice just for fun.
I mean where's the where's the
controversy with that? Were was the
American population consulted before
this war got started? Were we
Has Trump even come on TV and explained
to us why we have to put up with this
economic pain?
Has he come in and made the case for
this war that he started, not Congress.
Congress didn't declare this war. He
started this war on behalf of a foreign
nation for a foreign lobby
and our president, the American
president does not have the stones to
even come on and lie to us. Yeah, that's
I mean that's the thing. He doesn't even
think uh you know, we are even you know,
we're we're not even worth
like it's kind of like someone who's
like
you know, cheats on their wife and their
wife and and they don't even think they
owe their wife a lie about like where
they were last night. It's just like
where were you last night? Shut up. Make
my do my laundry, [__]
That's literally what it's like.
Adam 2, Ted who audits and holds if all
heads of branches of government are
implicated in the Epstein
scandal, Chief Justice Roberts in a
picture cuddling with Maxwell, rotten
top to bottom.
Who prosecutes this? I mean, it's
actually a miracle, Robbie, that even
we've gotten to see any files at all and
that there's even been like a law that
like has ordered the release of the
documents even though it hasn't been
complied with. I mean, it's a it's a
miracle that the pressure got anywhere
at all, but obviously the broader point
is yeah, the system is corrupt from top
to bottom and Epstein's only part of it.
Well, even Hitler cared about public
opinion polls.
Yeah, he did.
>> I'm so I mean there is that. No no king
stays king for very long if he doesn't
at least pretend to listen to the people
some of the time.
This is a great question, Robbie. Edward
Clark, sorry to step on you there. You
know, sometimes people you know, when
we're doing this through the StreamYard
link, you know, there's like a slight
there's like a half-second delay and so
that ends up like you know, John will be
saying something and I'll step on him
saying something and it's cuz I don't
know he's still talking and it's a
little bit. So that's kind of like why
that happens. Anyway, Adam 2, who sorry
that we already had that one. Um
Edward Clark is just joining in.
Thoughts on boots on the ground in Iran
and did you see Carolyn Levitt talking
about drafting soldiers?
You know, a week ago I would have said
there's no chance we're going to have
boots on the ground, I'm not so sure
now, Robbie. I mean, I think it's
entirely possible. I mean, they're
they're greasing the skids for it by
saying that there's not going to be any
other way to secure
the uranium stockpiles that may still be
buried under that collapsed nuclear
facility.
I mean, at this point it wouldn't
surprise me. And that's one of the
things that I I kind of got into a
debate, you know, with my pastor at
church. I'm like, the most Christian
evangelicals, he's he's a Zionist. I am
not.
And he was talking about, you know, how
it is it is our duty
under the Abrahamic covenant
to support Israel. And so, my pushback
to that was, okay, well, let let's just
pretend for a moment that we don't live
in a theocracy.
Instead, we supposedly live under a
republic.
Do you think Congress should be required
to declare war? You call yourself a
conservative.
He couldn't give me an answer.
And so,
to answer your question, it nothing
would surprise me at this point. If if
Trump decided if if Trump said tomorrow
that the Iranian people have failed,
they're not fighting for themselves,
they're being oppressed or whatever, and
if he says that we need 200,000 troops
to go into Iran,
I could see it happening.
And I don't see any pushback from either
political party.
I don't think there'll be a draft,
though.
Um you know, I don't I don't think
there's going to be like a massive I
mean, we do have a pretty large standing
army. And
they don't I think a draft is where you
would get resistance, right? I mean,
during the Vietnam War, it's the last
time we had an active military draft.
It's because, like, you know, middle
class and working class and rich white
people,
not so much the last group, um but still
some of them had to see watch their sons
go off to war and sometimes come back in
in bags and you know, flag-draped
coffins. And that's what really drove
the opposition to the war.
But here's the difference though. Back
in the '60s, we actually had this thing
called an economy.
We don't have that anymore. There's a
lot of people now who are unemployed,
who are underemployed, who are barely
scraping by.
And if Uncle Sam said, "Hey, if you
If If you join today or if you get
drafted, we'll pay you $80,000 a year
for this because you get combat pay and
everything else." How many people would
sign up for that?
A lot. Robbie, we're having We're the
stock market's now been open for 3
minutes. We're in the middle of a major
sell-off.
The stock market is New York The Dow
Jones Industrial Average has plunged 552
points. That's over 1% of overall market
value
in just a few minutes. S&P 500's down
1%. Nasdaq down .88.
The New York The New York Stock Exchange
Composite Index down 1.19. We haven't
found the floor yet. It's still It's
still falling. We're at 46,974.
We'll keep you up to date on that. So,
if I'm I mean, if I'm the If I'm a
Republican congressman, I'm like,
we better not have these elections.
Well, I mean Well, if I Well,
if I was If I was the um
If I was in Congress
and I had a Democratic challenger, I
would just straight up ask him, "Where
would you differ with my policies? Where
would you vote against me?
What What is it that I am doing that you
would do differently?
Would you vote for war powers
resolution?
Would you vote for a for a balanced
budget amendment? Would you, Mr.
Democrat, vote for any of the things
that people care about? Would you vote
for universal healthcare?
If the answer is no, why should I vote
for you?
Good question. So,
thank you again for tuning in to the
program with Ted Rall and John Kiriakou.
If you're just joining us, Robbie West
is filling in for John Kiriakou who
was traveling this morning and was
hoping to join us for at least part of
the show.
And I don't I'm assuming he's probably
not going to make it at this point, but
anything's possible. If he does, we'll
pop him right in. Robbie, do we have any
ads by any chance? I will check and see.
We got some piling up here on the back
end chat. So, I'll look at that see if
there's anything that grabs your
sweet little brain. Um as let's see.
Nixon Pro 4339, thanks for the $2.79
Canadian. As a Canadian, what do you
guys think of Carney?
Um
>> He's He's a clown.
Uh I do think he's like
I do think he's
you know, he gave a good speech that
time. That's about it. Yeah. That's
about all I can say.
Sneaker Dad's asking, does Ted Ted does
Clovis watch the YouTube cat TV channel?
So, I did show that to him one time and
he will never be allowed to watch it
again because he almost broke my all my
computer. He was going back and forth
from the front and then to the back to
see where the birds and small animals
were and it he wouldn't stop meowing and
it was just driving me absolutely
insane. I'm like uh no. No more. All
right. We got the ad up then the ad is
up now. Okay, thanks. All right. So,
today's sponsor is the Chicago Steak
Company and they're giving away four
free steaks on every order. The code is
BPSIR
FREE. Do you ever buy steaks at the
grocery store and it's just a total
gamble? You're standing there staring at
shrink-wrapped mystery cuts trying to
figure out which one might actually be
decent. And half the time you get home,
cook it and it's just fine. Nothing
special. Chicago Steak Company is the
opposite of that. USDA prime and upper
choice hand selected by butchers in
Chicago what aged 28 to 40 days vacuum
sealed and shipped on dry ice right to
your door. Every cut is hand carved no
guessing. Here's the part I really like.
Spend $199 or more any steaks your
choice use code BPSIRFREE
and they throw in four bourbon
peppercorn sirloins for free plus free
shipping. These are 6 oz top sirloins
with a cracked peppercorn and bourbon
rub lean beefy bold flavor throw them on
a hot grill and they're done in minutes.
That's $160 in free steaks 15,000 five
star reviews. These guys are the real
deal. Go to mychicagosteak.com/rumble
code BPSIRFREE
that's BPSIRFREE.
The link is in the description.
Okay, still no John Kiriakou and he's in
my mark my messages to him are still not
marked delivered. So I'm assuming we're
not going to hear from him. Let's talk
about the ecocide aspect of all this. So
over the weekend the United States and
Israel blew up four oil depots and a
petroleum logistics site
in and outside of the city of Tehran
deliberately triggering an ecological
disaster in a city of over 9 million
people. There's thick black smoke
covering the city soot covered streets
and cars balconies filled with black
gunk and toxic air filled lungs. And of
course these toxic chemicals have now
led already to acid rain people who've
been hit are being told to stay inside.
They're supposed to I don't know how
they're supposed to have their
revolution and overthrow the government
if they're going to be inside and have
like basically acid oil rain burning
their skin but I you know Donald Trump
didn't think that through. Um food
supplies, water reservoirs are being
contaminated. Um the sewers are all
going to have to be completely cleaned
out. Desalination plant in this in a
country with a horrible horrific drought
problem is uh is is out of commission.
So, you can um as someone who suffers
from asthma, I can only imagine how
horrific this is for people who have
respiratory disease and how much more
pulmonary and heart disease is going to
spread, how much cancer. I mean, this is
a war crime by definition. You're not
supposed to do this. It's There's a word
for it. It's called ecocide. The
deliberately deliberate targeting of a
um
facility with the knowledge that you
will precipitate an ecological disaster.
Um
This is I mean, obviously, we have no UN
worth a [__] There's no international
authority that's going to hold anyone to
account. UN Security Council won't do
dick.
Um and and we live in a in a world where
might meet might might makes right has
never been truer.
I have a question for you, Ted. Mhm.
During the the the Ukraine war, there's
this thing it's it's still happening,
actually.
If the Russians did this to the Ukis,
what would the reaction be from the
international community? Outrage.
>> But because they could.
The Russians could 100% do to the to the
Ukrainians what the United States is
Israel doing to Iran right now.
So, can you explain to me why this
double standard exists? Well, the Ukis
kind of tried to do it to the Russians,
right? Cuz the Russians occupy uh
Chernobyl, right? And uh and the and
Zaporizhzhia, where they have the
nuclear plant. Um
and the Ukrainians um
uh
targeted and have hit those facilities.
There was actually um
the International Atomic Energy uh
Commission was concerned that they
might, you know, create a meltdown.
Unfortunately, it didn't happen. Um I
guess nobody cared cuz it was the
Ukrainians and the Russians would have
been
Russian-held Ukraine would have been the
area that would have been
affected. Um
yeah, I mean obviously it's it's total
hypocrisy. This is the kind of thing I
mean even Lindsey Graham uh warned
cautioned that this was going too far.
Well, he doesn't care about the people.
He cares about the PR blowback. He He
doesn't want the the Israelis to look
any worse than international media that
what they already do. So, I mean
>> I don't know how it's possible.
Well, I don't know either. I mean you go
out, you commit a a genocide, then you
drag the world superpower in to go fight
a war on your behalf, and
I mean none of that none of that
matters.
I think he's worried about nothing
because honestly nobody cares. Uh the
Gulf states don't care.
Yeah. Uh as far as I can tell, I mean I
could be 100% be wrong on this, the
Islamic ummah doesn't care.
If they do, why aren't they calling for
jihad against Israel? I don't see a call
for jihad. I don't see I don't see the
Muslim world rising up with one voice
saying we're going to put an end to
this. And there's a billion Muslims.
They could do it.
Where are they? I don't see anyone. As
you pointed out, I'm a commie, and man
if we ever needed a revolution
or 10 of them or 100 of them, it's now.
Um Tim A question for you Robbie from
Tatum Hedrick. What are the best levers
for the people to pull back the fourth
branch? The states.
Local elections and vote people in to
state office who actually understand the
concept of of states' rights and who are
not bought off by by lobbies.
That's the only hope that we have. Start
with your county with your your county
sheriff because he's the supreme law
enforcement in in your in your county.
And then go from there. Elect state
legislatures that care. Your school
board elections matter more than
probably any other election in in the
country, honestly.
Uh people aren't used to hearing that.
We always focus on national elections.
Your local elections are so much more
important because they directly impact
you and how you live and where you live.
And that's how you do it. You have to
tear this thing down brick by brick. The
question is do we have the time to do
it? It's very very late in the day and I
don't know.
Beef Mama is asking, do we think that
the Middle East region wants US bases to
leave? I think it depends on the country
and it depends on you know, it's it's a
complicated story. People don't speak as
one. Um I think you know, some some
countries are more pro US US than
others. There's always a split between
governments and their people, but that
split's different, you know, it's
different in Bahrain than it is in Qatar
than it is in Jordan than it is in the
in the uh in the UAE, you know?
Well, I think that the problem with the
Islamic countries is the same problem
that Europe has. Uh they don't like the
ugly American, but they love the
security blanket that the ugly that the
ugly American provides. And if the US
pulls out, do you have to defend
yourself? And who wants to do that when
you can live off the tit of the United
States and outsource your security to a
foreign power?
F E says
>> No, militaries are expensive. Sorry
about it.
Militaries are expensive.
And you have to pay for it.
>> True, but but also a US military base
also makes your country a target as
we're seeing right now. Yeah, to an
extent. I mean, sure. I mean, you might
get a hotel blown up, but who's going to
invade you? The answer is nobody.
F E says, thanks for the two bucks. Just
got a ticket for the Sex Pistols playing
San Diego in October. Original members
except for John Lydon. Yeah, but
saying original members except for John
Lydon when you're talking about the Sex
Pistols is like saying like founding
fathers does not include Thomas
Jefferson. Um
I don't know. You kind of have to have
John Lydon, but um I I saw the Sex
Pistols reunion show. I guess this was
in 96, I want to say. It was fantastic,
but it did have John Lydon. Uh people
they started about 20 minutes late at
Roseland in New York City and people
were getting spicy and at one point
before the concert Johnny Johnny Rotten
/ Lydon came out and he's like You've
already waited 20 [__] years for
this. You can wait a
a few more [__] minutes.
He had to be
>> I have a I have a question for you Ted.
This is something I've been thinking
about over the weekend.
Iran is a BRICS member.
Do you see
that actually factoring into the
equation? Will Iran's I guess you can
call them allies. I don't really know at
this point.
Could they meaningfully help Iran? Is
there anything they could do
economically to assist them besides
write an externally worded letter to the
UN which nobody's going to read? Well, I
mean in the long run if the government
if in the short run probably not, but in
the long run yeah, if the Iranian
government uh
survives for sure. I mean they can prop
up the
the Iranian currency. They can provide
low interest or zero interest loans.
You know, they can the Chinese can build
stuff. The Chinese engineers could go in
and help with the cleanup operation.
There's a lot of stuff that like you
know, allied countries could do for
sure.
You know, I mean I and I could see I
really could see Russia and China
stepping forward in a post-war scenario
if the US gets the [__] out. I mean they
don't want to risk
neither President Putin nor Xi want to
risk World War III
>> with Donald Trump. Um but as long as
we're there involved involved in combat
operations, they're not going to come.
But if things settle down,
yeah. I I I think so. What do you think?
Well, after the fact, sure. But I mean
that's just like me help that's like me
coming to your house with a fire hose
after your house has burned down. It's
oh, I'm here to help. Well, I mean you
know, I might need a place to stay. I
might need your help to cart stuff away.
It's not like there's nothing to do
after a situation like that, but I hear
you. I I take your point. Uh Mark and
Roll uh 95 50 44, only atheists should
hold high offices. Religious fanatics
are disqualified. I'll laugh at you and
Stalin and Mao Zedong.
Um
uh question guys uh from Desert Fox.
What do you think about the chances of a
false flag on US oil on US soil?
I mean, if you're going to suspend your
elections, you've got to do it for
national security reasons.
And we already had that that uh
dude in Texas, you know, running around
shooting people and causing all kinds of
trouble of uh trouble and havoc. Why
can't you do that more, whether it's a
false flag or actual
people who just for whatever reason
become radicalized and want to go out
and just start causing, you know,
mayhem.
Maybe you have yourself a nice attack on
Independence Day or something. Who can
Who knows? Um I just thought it was
worth noting. I don't know if there's
much commentary to be made, but uh
Robbie, this report from the National
Intelligence Council
uh was commissioned before the US and
Israeli attack on Iran.
And they were asked to say, "What do you
think is likely to happen from this
war?"
Um and their assessment was it's highly
unlikely that the Iranian government
will be overthrown, even if you kill the
Ayatollah.
And uh
I mean, so, you know, they they they
knew their own government had told them
you're probably not going to get regime
change. So,
is it reasonable to conclude that the
Trump administration isn't really that
interested in the regime change? I mean,
look at Venezuela. They weren't really
interested in regime change. They were
just interested in presidential and
first lady kidnapping. People always
forget, by the way, we kidnapped
Maduro's wife, too. We still have her.
I mean, but it comes to Iran, honestly,
I don't think the United States is
interested in in regime change. I think
that we want two things. One, to appease
the Israel lobby. We want Iran to stop
being a sovereign nation. We want them
to give up a any
any semblance of of a military.
And second, we want them to open up
their borders and allow us to send our
oil companies in. This is about us
taking the oil. It's just like what what
it was in Venezuela. Trump
he actually had a moment of honesty.
Where he said, "We went in there to take
the oil."
This is about taking the oil because the
United States dollar is pegged to the
dollar. By the way, um I think John's
delay in joining us might be tied into
one of the news events. And I you know,
all over XE, I know you've seen this
too, Robbie.
Um right-wingers have been Republicans,
I should say, have been complaining um
about the closure of the Department of
Homeland Security. There's massive lines
at a lot of airports. Uh
you know, there was a 5-hour line and at
some airports over the weekend at TSA
because a lot of TSA officers are
involved in a sickout or a slowdown cuz
they're not getting paid.
Uh and it's all due to the showdown with
between the Democrats who've imposed a
partial government shutdown over
requesting um some reforms to ICE that
Republicans don't want to grant. Um you
know, so I wouldn't be surprised if if
John is like stuck in TSA hell right
now. Now, I want y'all to think about
this real quick. Seriously, I want y'all
to think about what what Ted just said.
The Democrats are having a tantrum doing
a partial government shutdown not over
the fact that a imperial president has
taken their power and has led us into an
undeclared war in violation of the
Constitution. But instead are butt hurt
over enforcement of immigration law.
Think about what I just said.
They do not care
about the economic hardship and pain
being inflicted on the American people.
They do not care about losing their
power to the executive. They do not care
about anything except for their pet
topics.
That is unsustainable and that's why
you cannot explain to me why I should
vote for either party.
Well, as you know, Robbie, I I'm well, I
think ISIS really out of control and
even you've agreed about that that their
tactics suck. Because they are. And uh
but like but I take your broader point
here, which is that uh you know, this is
a Look, as heinous as ISIS been, this
issue with Iran is a lot bigger and it
has much bigger repercussions in terms
of murdering innocent people in Iran and
not just school girls. I count
everybody. I mean, you know, one of the
things I don't like is like, well, look,
it's just children and and women and
children are getting injured. Look, even
when we blow up like uh you know, a
member of the of the Revolutionary
Guards, that dude is just doing his
[__] job and means no harm to us at
all and we have no business killing him,
right? But uh but but you're right about
the economics. Speaking of which, it
looks like the um stock fall off has uh
pretty much leveled off for today, but
it's not pretty. Dow Jones Industrial
Average currently at 46,794
uh with a 1.5% drop. This is a 700-point
fall. Just bear in mind, we were at
50,000. Now we're well under 47,000.
So, the Dow the Dow is going to It's
just one thing after another. Uh you
know, oil is over well over $100 a
barrel. It peaked out at 120 a barrel at
one point uh in futures trading. So, I
mean, we're going to have to bring
Achilles back and uh have to explain to
people a little bit about like you know,
uh Achilles' job is is uh you know, is
is to help people manage who have money
manage their money.
Um, you know, he's not here to discredit
capitalism. That's my job. Um
Anyway, let's um More and more it's my
job.
Right. Right. Yeah, apparently. Um
Matina, question for me. Is this about
making the dollar stronger? The war.
Ah,
well, I mean, I I I don't think
I mean, I don't think it will. I mean,
there's a this scenario in in the old
days with with the uh petrodollar that
you know, the idea was the higher oil
prices propped up the dollar. But, uh
you know, we don't we don't we don't
have that we don't live in that world
anymore. So,
and also, I don't think the United
States wants a strong dollar because
that discourages uh you know, people the
trade with other countries. Uh a strong
dollar makes US goods more expensive,
and we're like, you know, this president
is obsessed with the trade imbalances.
Well, I mean, a stronger dollar is not
going to help with that. What do you
think?
What goods do we make?
I mean, serious question.
What do we make here? Do we make shoes
in this country? Do you make Do we make
electronics? Do we make cell phones? Do
we make TVs? Do we actually build 100%
of our cars here? What do we build?
We still make things, but far fewer than
we used to, obviously.
>> Trump Trump's biggest betrayal, Trump's
biggest lie was that when when he was at
when he first ran for 20 in 2016, when I
supported him, I was one of Trump's
biggest supporters. He said, "I am going
to bring all of these jobs back, and I
am going to be laser-focused on the
American people."
He won me in 2016 on that on that
Valentine's Day debate, where he called
George W. Bush a war criminal to Jeb's
face. It was beautiful.
>> And I'm like, yes, that's the man for
me.
Now, here we are,
almost 10 years later
and Trump has completely
betrayed his country. He's betrayed his
base. He's betrayed his oath and for
what? Our economy is weaker. No jobs
have come back. We are now fighting
other countries' wars again.
We are still supporting Europe's
Europe's defense again. We're in a proxy
war with Russia that Trump has not ended
after saying he would end it in a day,
which by the way, he could by cutting
off the Ukis. He won't do it. And now
we're fighting a war for his butt buddy
Bibi.
I mean
No. No, I look I I have nothing to add
to that cuz it's I agree with you. Um
No, the dollar's screwed. What supports
it? We It's a lead-based standard. We
don't have an oil-based standard
anymore. It's a lead-based standard. You
do what we say or we delete you.
That's true.
Uh so, Vilmar Air, what's the off-ramp
for Trump at this point? Um canceling
the elections.
Um thanks for
thoughts on potential Samson option. Um
Yeah, well, that would be like where the
Israelis decide to like basically go
full use their nuclear weapons. I think
it's entirely possible, right? I mean um
although I don't think we're there yet.
Uh it's not likely. Possible and likely
are not the same thing. We got to talk
about Cuba in the 5 minutes we have
left, Robbie. And you have all the stuff
you need for the raid, I assume. Yep,
I'm getting it. I'll put together as we
speak. Okay, cool. All right, so um
Yes, Robbie. Thanks for the dollar from
months on Pat. I told you it would
happen and you heard it, read it, but
you can call me anti-Semitic it was
anti-Semitic regret it. Nope, said it.
Yep, we have to tear this [__]
um
uh up. Ice tube Ice Cube, I think you
mean. Um
Trent uh
is of course our other producer. Robbie,
what do you think about reports that US
commanders are openly invoking
Armageddon as an even as since you're an
evangelical, you of course you know this
whole statement.
I think it's irresponsible and I think
it's stupid and people who are saying
this have no idea what the Bible says.
Well,
sorry, go ahead. Well, it's
First of all, there was a battle of
Armageddon during World War I.
And that did not bring about the end of
the world. Armageddon happen happens
after after the millennial reign of
Christ. Armageddon does not happen
before that. So, trying to force it is
not going to make it happen and Jesus
does not need your help by the way to
come back. He will do it on his
timetable when he's ready to because he
is God.
Oh, there is that, right? There is that.
Um, okay, so let's talk about Cuba. So,
um, there's reporting, I mean of course
this is sort of like one of those
reports that might come and go and like,
you know, there'll never be any
follow-up and we'll never hear anything
about but according to USA Today,
they're reporting that there Trump
administration is leaking information
about negotiations for between President
Miguel Diaz-Canel
where he would basically agree to
resign. The Castro family would allow be
allowed to remain on Cuba if they would
like to.
And that basically Cuba would turn into
a vassal state.
All of its ports, energy and tourism
would basically become US property to be
looted and exploited. It would
essentially return to the state that it
was on in under Batista in the 1950s and
before the communist revolution in the
late 1950s.
Um,
it's gross. I believe the reporting. How
likely do you think this is to happen?
I mean, it it depends on how distracted
the United States gets fighting Israel's
wars for it.
I mean, if if the United States could
could focus
the the
Cuba would no longer be an independent
state by now. They they they've already
been collapsed. They would they've
already be over. The one thing that the
Cubans have going for them is that the
American foreign policy apparatus is
effectively
autistic.
We cannot stick to one
coherent policy for more than 20 minutes
over the world playing whack-a-mole,
fighting fighting invisible enemies that
only they can see
for special interests that pay them.
And so, if there's one thing that the
Cubans have going for them, it's not
their geography, it's not their natural
resources, they don't have any. It's the
ineptitude of the American foreign
policy blob.
Well, we'll just see what happens there.
Thanks everyone for watching the program
with Ted Rall and John Kiriakou.
I'm assuming John will be back in I'm
sure he'll be back tomorrow.
He see he's stuck between planes. Never
heard back from his from him from my
texts and phone calls and not
everything's marked as delivered, so
he's obviously stuck on a plane
somewhere or in a TSA checkpoint from
hell.
Hope there's no strip searching going
on.
Anyway, please stay tuned to the TMI
show with Manila Chan and myself and
producer Robbie West will be there, too.
If you are on YouTube and you want to
become a tier two
donor member, you check the click that
membership tab, choose tier two, you
will be in the closing credits as a
thank you. I'm about to play those
credits right now, so you'll see exactly
what you'd be getting. Thanks, Robbie.
>> Mhm.